# BEAU HODES

CONTACT

BEAUHODES@GMAIL.COM

(816) 377-1824

**BEAUHODES.COM** 

# PROFILE

I am a computer science student at the University of Kansas with an interest in software development and finding creative business solutions for new technology. I also have experience with full stack development, basic game development, and machine learning. I am a very quick, motivated learner who thrives in a fast-paced environment and enjoys complex problem solving.

# EDUCATION

**BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, COMPUTER SCIENCE** 

### **EXPECTED MAY 2021**

UNIVERSITY OF KANSAS | LAWRENCE, KS GPA: 3.86 MAJOR, 3.81 OVERALL ACT: 33

# SKILLS

- Python
- C++/C
- SQL
- TensorFlow
- Linux/Git
- HTML/CSS
- Web Technologies
- JavaScript/Node.js
- Cloud: GCP/Azure
- Data Structures/Algorithms

# PROJECTS

### TRENDING WORDS BOT

JANUARY 2021

· Uses JavaScript, Python, and various APIs to monitor keyword-related chatter on Google and Twitter and alert via phone or computer.

# PERSONAL SPEECH TRAINER

IN PROGRESS

• Uses a respiratory sensor and Python to help those who stutter, including myself, work on their fluency using computer visuals.

## **PROGMON**

NOVEMBER 2019

• Along with 4 classmates, created a basic fighting game, called Progmon, using Python and Pygame. My responsibilities included game flow design, computer logic, test suite development, and graphic design.

### **BETLIQUID**

IN PROGRESS

• BetLiquid will be an online exchange-based betting platform that allows users to predict the outcome of an event by buying shares in the end result. My responsibilities include data management and API development.

# **EXPERIENCE**

LOCKTON COMPANIES | JUNE 2020 - AUGUST 2020

- Lockton is the world's largest privately held insurance brokerage firm
- Worked on a variety of projects including nuclear verdict research, finding discrepancies in payment systems, and insurance-related case studies

### SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

PORT TMS | MAY 2019 - NOVEMBER 2019

- Port TMS is a cloud-based transportation management software company founded in 2018
- General programmer: Implemented, from back end to front end, a web interface for company developers to save time in the creation and management customer data reports

### **DATA ANALYTICS CONSULTANT**

ASTRA INNOVATIONS | NOVEMBER 2019 - FEBRUARY 2020

- Astra Innovations is a tech company that uses data analytics to help oil and gas wells become more efficient
- Selected relevant data from unconventional oil and gas well data using SQL queries
- Used Google Cloud Platform's AI Prediction Models and Python to find ways to improve drilling performance

### **WEB DESIGNER**

MIDLAND METAL | MAY 2017 - JULY 2017

- Midland metal is a manufacturer, importer, and distributor of fittings, nipples, valves, and accessories founded in 1980
- Communicated directly with clients to develop basic designs for their websites
- Implemented designs and using Wordpress and HTML

### KU LEADERSHIP CHALLENGE

JANUARY 2020

• Two day seminar promoting leadership skills and networking sponsored by corporate affiliates

# CERTIFICATES

### CRYPTOCURRENCY AND BLOCKCHAIN

UNIVERSITY OF PENNSYLVANIA (ONLINE) | JANUARY 2021

SEQUENCES, TIME SERIES, AND PREDICITON IN TENSORFLOW DEEPLEARNING.AI | AUGUST 2020

### **BLOOMBERG MARKET CONCEPTS**

BLOOMBERG LP | APRIL 2020

## IBM DATA SCIENCE PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATE

COURSERA/IBM | SEPTEMBER 2019

• Nine-course certificate using Python and various algorithms

MICROSOFT: AZURE207X —"DATABASES IN AZURE" EDX | MARCH 2019

# SFIFCTED COURSEWORK

- Software Engineering: Systematic development of software products including life-cycle models, teams, tools, testing, planning, and estimating. Also covered Agile development, and Git version-control.
- Others: Computer Algorithms, Data Structures, Machine Learning, Computer Security, Calculus I-III, Linear Algebra, Statistics, Operating Systems, Computer Architecture, Databases, Computer Forensics